# SHAHIN SHAIKH

## Summary

7+ years of experience in the IT industry, backed by B.E Information Technology and PGDAC. Hands on domain experience in the field of Finance risk solution, Online banking and Wealth Management. Working on Agile Methodology Model Good exposure to product Prototyping, Designing, Development, Unit Testing and Documentation. Experience at working independently, in a team-oriented, collaborative environment.

#### Experience

Exempt Non-Officer, Group CIO, 07/2021 - Current

Credit Suisse - Pune, India

Currently I am working on Cash Settlement Services which is part of cash strategic system and mainly worked on netting, approvals, scheduling payments and generating swift message.

Responsibilities towards product are like creating new microservices as per requirement, handling change requests, prod bug fixes, code review, Analyzing new functionality and providing solution on it, helping other team members whenever need and giving correct guidance.

o Senior Software Engineer, 08/2019 - 07/2021

TietoEvry India Pvt. Ltd. - Pune, India

I was part of Private Nettbank & Nettbank Bedrift-Norway which is Nordea Corporate Banking services is providing banking integration services for corporate customers in nordea -online nettbanking portal for small and medium norwegian corporate customers.

In this project I worked on Change Request which comes from business team, code review, Designing and Development of Controller, services, interfaces etc.

Troubleshooting the Issue and provided the solution at real time

Software Development Engineering, Associate, 04/2016 - 08/2019

Fiserv India Pvt. Ltd. - Pune, India

I Worked on SmarterPay application and it is developed to allow for a financial institution to set overdraft limits based on an account's probability of charge-off (POCO) and their capacity to repay (CTR).

Technology used for this project are Core Java, SQL Server, PMML Trees. Also I developed one project which is SmartConfig in Angular5 and Spring boot and for internal use for SmarterPay

Responsibilities towards the project are Requirement analysis, estimations, Designing, developing and Unit Testing.

### Education

Bachelor Of Engineering In Information Technology

Pune University, Passing Score – 66.33

HSC, 2010

Maharash

tra Board,

**Passing** 

Score -

72.33

SSC, 2008

Maharash

tra Board,

**Passing** 

Score -

77.69%

PG-DAC, Diploma in Advance Computing, 2015

Infoway, Pune, Passing score - 68.38

### Contact

Address: Pune, India 413102

Phone: +91-9921320029

Email: shahin20170122@gmail.com

### Skills

Technology - Core Java, J2EE, Spring MVC, Spring boot microservices, Typescript, REST full web services, javascript.

Language - Angular 5, HTML5, CSS Database - SQL, Oracle Servers/Platform - Tomcat,

Kafka, WebLogic,

# Certifications

Oracle Certifie Professional, Java SE 8 Programmer I Azure Fundamentals Certifie

# • Hobbies

- In free Time I would Like to do Workout
- trekking, Travelling